The next thing I want to do is show you
the general attack on collision resistant
接下来我想讲一下一个有关碰撞连续哈希函数的普遍攻击
hash functions. If you remember when we
talked about block cyphers. We saw a
如果你记得我们曾讲到的流密码，
general attack on block cyphers which we
called exhaustive search. And that attack
我们明白有关流密码的普遍攻击――穷举搜索
forced the key size for a block cypher to
be 128 bits or more. Similarly on
这种攻击要求密钥的规模必须是2^128甚至更多
collision resistance there is a general
attack called the birthday attack which
类似的，有关碰撞连续性也有一个普遍攻击――生日攻击
forces the output of collision resistant
hash functions to be more than a certain
它要求碰撞连续哈希函数的输出必须是大于一个确定的界限
bound. So let me show you the attack and
we will see what those bounds come out to
所以，我来展示一下这种攻击方法并且我们将明白这些界限如何推导出
be. So here's the general attack that can
work on arbitrary collision resistant hash
这个普通攻击可以解决背离碰撞连续哈希函数
functions. So here we have our collision
resistant hash functions, supposedly, but
假设这里我们有我们的碰撞连续的哈希函数，
lets suppose that it outputs N bit values.
In other words, the output space is
并且假设它输出N个比特值。换句话说
roughly of size two to the N. Now, the
message space is gonna be much, much
输出空间的规模大概是2^N。现在明文空间必须远远大于N比特
larger than N bits. Let's just say that
the messages that are being hashed are
也就是说经过哈希的明文是N比特的100倍
say, you know, a hundred times N bits. I
wanna show you an algorithm that can find
我想给你们看一种算法
the collision for this hash function H in
time roughly two to the N over two. Okay,
可以以2^n/2的概率找到这个哈希函数H的密钥碰撞
so roughly the square root of the size of
the outputs space. So here's how the
约等于输出空间的平方根。这里是这种算法如何运算的
algorithms gonna work: what we'll do is
we'll choose random two to the N over two
我们需要做的是在我们的明文空间中
messages in our message space that's
called an M-one to M-two to the N over
随机选择2^2/N的明文子集：m1,m2...m n/2
two. Now because the messages themselves
are much bigger than N bits, they're
因为这个明文本身大于N比特，
hundred times N bits, it's very likely
that all these messages are distinct. So
即是N比特的100倍，很可能这些明文就是不寻常的
they'll be distinct with high probability.
But for each one of these messages we're
因此它们不同的概率很大。但是对于这些明文中的每一个值
gonna apply the hash function and obtain
the tag T sub I. So this is of course the
我们都经过哈希得到Ti。当然Ti是N比特长的字串
T sub I's are N-bit long strings. And now
we're gonna look for a collision among the
我们将在Ti中找一个碰撞密钥
T sub I's. In other words, we're gonna
find an I and a J such that T sub I equals
换句话说，我们已经得到I,J，并且Ti=Tj
to T sub J. And once we've done that we've
basically found the collision because, as
一旦我们这样做了之后实际上我们就找到了这个碰撞
we said, with very high probability, M-I
is not equal to M-J. But the hash of M-I
因为，Mi不等于Mj的可能性是很大的。但是
is equal to the hash of M-J and therefore
we found the collision on the function H.
哈希函数的Mi等于Mj，因此我们找到函数H的碰撞密钥
Now if it so happens that we looked
through all the two to the N over two T
现在如果这样那么我们查找明文Ti的所有2^2/n比特
sub I's and we don't find the collision,
we go back to step one and try another set
但找不到碰撞密钥，现在我们返回第一步并且
of two to the N over two messages. So the
question is how well will this work, in
尝试另一个2^2/n的明文序列，现在的问题是这种方法有多好
other words how many times do we have to
iterate this process until we actually
换句话说在我们找到这样的碰撞得重复这样的步骤多少次？
find the collision? And I wanna show you
that in fact the number of iterations is
我想给你们看一下实际这个重复的次数是很小很小的
gonna be very, very small which means that
this algorithm will find the collision in
也就意味着这种算法会以大约为2^n/2的概率及时找到碰撞密钥
time that's roughly proportional two to
the N over two. So to analyze this type of
所以为了分析攻击
attack, I have to tell you a little bit
about the birthday paradox. I imagine some
我不得不告诉你们一些有关生日悖论的知识。我想
of you have already heard about the
birthday paradox. Here stated as a
你们中有人已经听过生日悖论。正如这个定理
theorem, and I wanna prove it to you
because everybody should see a proof of
所说的那样，并且我想给你们证明一下，因为每一个人
the birthday paradox at least once in
their lives. So here it is, so imagine we
在他们的生活中至少看到一个有关生日悖论的证明。这里
have N random variables R-one to R-N in
the interval one to B. And the only thing
假设我们有N个随机变量r1到rN属于区间，
I'm gonna assume about them is that
they're actually independent of one
关于它们我唯一假设的是它们之间是独立的
another. That's crucial that these N
samples R-one to R-N in this interval are
这N个样本值之间相互独立是核心问题
independent of one another. And they also
happen to be distributed identically. So
并且恰巧它们是均等分配的
for example, they might all be uniform in
the interval one to B, but again these
例如，在区间内它们可能都是一致的
would be independently uniform variables.
Now it so happens that if we set N to B
但是同样他们都是独立一致的变量。所以如果我们
about the square root of B, in other words
if we sample roughly the square root of B
设n=为B的平方根，换句话说如果我们从区间[0，B]
samples from the interval one to B, And to
be precise, it's one point two times the
中大概抽取根号B个样本，更精确得说是1.2倍的根号B，
square root of B. Then the probability
that two of those samples will be the same
之后这些样本中的两个数相等的概率至少为1/2
is at least a half. Okay, then it turns
out in fact the uniform distribution is
现在证明了一致分配实际是生日悖论最遭的例子。换句话说
the worst case for the birthday paradox.
In other words, if the distribution from
如果取自Ri样本的分配不一致
which the R-I's are sampled from is
non-uniform, that in fact fewer than one
那么实际上小于
point two times the square root of B
samples are needed. The uniform
1.2倍的根号B的样本是需要的
distribution is the worst case. So we're
gonna prove this for the uniform
这个一致分配是最遭的案例。我们已经证明了有关一致分配
distribution and that basically also
proves it for all other distributions. But
也证明了对于所有的分配情况
the proof that I wanna show you here will
hold just for the uniform distribution.
但是我给出的证明仅仅针对于一致分配
Okay, so let's do the proof that's
actually not difficult at all. So we're
好的，让我们证明一下，其实一点也不难。
asking what is the probability that there
exists an I that is not equal to J such
我们会问存在一个I不等于J但是哈希I等于哈希J的概率是多少
that RI is equal to RJ. Well, let's negate
that so it's basically one minus the
所以让我们从对立面入手，即1减去
probability that for all I not equal to J
we have that RI is not equal to RJ. This
所有I不等于J，但哈希I等于哈希J的概率
basically means that no collision occurred
among the N samples that we chose. Well
这实际意味着在我们选择的N个样本中没有碰撞发生
let's try to write this out more
precisely. Well we're gonna write this as
好，让我们试着更精确地写出来。我们已经写在这1减。
one minus. And now when we choose R-one,
basically it's the first one we choose so
现在当我们第一个选择R1时
it's not gonna collide with anything. But
now let's look at what happens when we
它不和任何其他的值冲突，现在让我们看看
choose R-two, when we choose R-two, lemme
ask you, what is the probability that
当我们选择R2，我问你，R2不和R1冲突的概率是多少？
R-two. Does not collide with R-one. Well,
R-one takes one slot so there are B minus
好的，R1占一个位置，
one slots that if R-two falls into it's
not gonna collide with R-one. So in other
如果R2掉入不与R1冲突时所以是B减1位置，换句话说
words the probability that R-two does not
collide with R-one is B minus one slot
R2与R1不冲突的概率是(B-i)除以B,
divided by all B possible slots.
Similarly, when we pick R-three What is
类似的，当我们选择R3,与R1，R2不冲突的概率是多少？
the probability that R-three does not
collide with either R-one or R-two? Again,
同样R1，R2占两个位置。
R-one and R-two take up two slots. And so
there are B minus two slots that remain
之后概率是B减去
for R-three if it falls into either one of
those B minus two slots it's not gonna
如果R3与B减去与R1，R2不冲突的两项的剩余的两项，
collide with either R-one or R-two. So I
imagine you see the pattern now, so R-four
我假想你们已经明白这个模式
it's probability of not colliding with
R-one, R-two, or R-three is B minus three
所以R4与R1，R2，R3都不冲突的概率是
over B. And so on and so forth until we
get to the very last R-N and the
B减去这三项除以B，等等一直到很大的Rn,
probability that R-N does not collide with
the previous R-I's, well, there are N
Rn与之前的Ri个值不冲突的概率是
minus one slots taken up by the previous
R-I's. So, if R-N falls into any of the
N减去之前Ri个值所占的比例，所以如果Rn掉进
remaining B minus N plus one slots It's
not gonna collide with any of the previous
剩下部分的任何一个，B减N加一项与之前的R1到Rn-1都不冲突
R-one to R-N minus one. Now you notice
that the reason I was able to multiply all
现在你们注意到我能把所有这些可能性乘起来的原因是
these probabilities is exactly because the
R-I's are all independent of one another.
因为这Ri个值相互独立的。
So it's crucial for the step That the
R-I's are independent. So let me rewrite
在这一步中这Ri项相互独立是至关重要的
this expression a little bit. Let me write
it as one minus the product of I goes to N
所以让我重写一下这个表达：1减从i到n-1项的1-i/B之和，好的
minus one of one minus I over B. Okay. All
I did is I just rewrote this as a big
我做的这些仅仅是重新写一下这一大项
product as opposed to writing the terms
individually. So now I'm gonna use the
它们是这些对立事件的单独项之和。
standard inequality that says that for any
positive X, one minus X is less than E to
它们是这些对立事件的单独项之和。
the minus X. And that's actually easy to
see because E to the minus X, if you look
1-X小于e^负X，很容易看出，因为如果你看一下e^负X的泰勒展开
at it's Taylor expansion, is one minus X
plus X squared over two minus and so on
是1-x+(x^2)/2-...等等
and so forth. And so you can see that
we're basically ignoring this latter part
显然看得出我们实际是忽略了泰勒展开的后面部分
of the Taylor expansion, which happens to
be positive and as a result the left side
省略的部分恰巧是正的，结果
is gonna be smaller than the right-hand
side. Okay, so let's plug this inequality
左边小于右边。好的，让我们堵上这个不等式
in, and what do we get? We get that this
is greater than one minus the product of I
我们得到了什么？我们得到了这是大于1减从i=1到i=n-1项e的负i/b的积
goes from one to N minus one of E to the
minus I over B okay, simply plugged in X
可直接放入X集合中的等于I/B
equals I over B for each one of those
terms. And the next thing about
的所有项。接下来的话我们会发现关于指数的知识是
exponentials is that we multiply them, the
exponents add. As a result this is simply
我们把指数相乘，指数相加。结果上就是
equal to one minus E to the power of, here
let me take the one over B out of the
简单地等于1减去e的负i/b的和次方，这里我们把1到B从括号中取出
parentheses, sum of I goes from one to N
minus one of I. Okay. So, all I did was I
然后对于从1到n-1项求和。我要做的就是我把-1/b从括号中拿出来
took the minus one over B out of the
parentheses and we're left with simple sum
同时我们留下了从1到n-1项的和
of one to N minus one. And so the sum of
the integers from N to N minus one is
所以从n到n-1项的和
simply N times N minus one over two which
it can bound by N squared over two. And so
是简单地n倍的n-1项，这样可以约束N的次数超过二
really what I get at the end here is one
minus E to the power of minus N squared
所以我最后真的得到的是1减e的负2b分之n的二次方。
over two B. Okay, I literally downed it to
sum here by N squared over two. Okay, very
我实际上把n的次数降到了2.非常好
good. So now what do we do about N squared
over two B? Well, we can derive exactly
所以我们应该怎么处理2b分之n的平方呢？我们可以确切的
what N squared over two B is from the
relationship here. So if you think about
从这块的关系式中得到它的结果。如果考虑这样做，
it, let's look at N squared over two.
Well, N squared over two is 1.2 squared
我们先来解决2分之n平方。二分之n的平方就是二分之1.2的平方。
over two. 1.2 squared is 1.44 divided by
two is .72 times the square root of B
1.2的平方就是1.44再除以二是0.72。再乘以b的平方的算术平方根，
squared which is B. Okay so N squared over
two is .72B, and as a result, N squared
那就是B。太好了，那2分之N的平方就是0.72B.作为结果，2B分之N的平方
over 2B is just .72. So we get 1-E, which
is a power of minus 0.72. Well so now you
只是0.72。我们就得到了结果是1减0.72次方的e。
just plug this in to your calculator and
you get 0.53, which as far as i know, is
所以现在就把这个结果带入你的计算式你就会得到大于F
always bigger than F. So this proves the
Birthday Paradox and you notice that it
的0.53。所以这就证明了生日悖论，你也会注意到
was crucial to a string that the samples
are independent of one another, we only
对于字符串来说样本是独立于其他的非常重要，我们呢
proved that for the uniform distribution.
But as i said it is actually fairly easy
只能证明它们是均匀分布的。但是正如我所说的这是非常容易讨论的
to argue now that any distribution that is
away from the uniform distribution will
远离平均分布的任意分布总可以
satisfy this with even a lower balance. So
if you have. 1.2 squared of B, the theorem
满足一个更低的平衡。所以如果你有b的1.2次方，这个定律
will certainly hold for none uniform
distributions. The reason it is called a
就会不适用于平均分布。之所以叫做
paradox is because it is very paradoxical
that the square root function grows very
悖论是因为平方根函数的增长很缓慢是与此矛盾的
slowly. In particular if you try to apply
this to birth dates, so lets assume that
特殊的如果你尝试去提供一个生日日期，让我们假设我们
we have a number of people in a room, and
lets assume that their birth dates are
有很多人在一个房间里，继续假设他们的
independent of one another and are uniform
in their interval one through 365. Then
生日彼此独立并且平均分配在1到365的区间内。
what the Birthday Paradox says is that we
need roughly 1.2 times the square root of
生日悖论说的是我们需要大约1.2倍的365的平方根，
365. Which i believe is something like 23,
which says we need roughly 23 people in a
我相信就是23左右，也就是说我们需要大约23个人在
room, and then with probability one half,
two of them will actually have the same
一间屋子里，他们有一半的可能，会有两个人的生日是相同的。
birth date. The reason it is called a
paradox is because the number 23 seems
这个理论被称为悖论的原因是23看上去
really small to people, and yet by this
theorem we just proved, with probability
对于人们来说太小了，而对于我们刚证明的理论来说
one half, there will be two people with
the same birth date. By the way the
将会有一半的机会会有两个人用相同的生日。顺便说一下，
intuition for why this fact is true is
because really what the collision is
直觉告诉我们为什么这个事实是成立的是因为
counting is it is looking at all possible
pairs of people. And if you have a square
所有可能的人群生日配对是随机碰撞的。如果你已经知道了
root of B people, then there are square
root of B squared pairs. Roughly, Which is
b人群的平方根，这就是b平方配对的平方根。大约就是b人群配对的总数
roughly B pairs total and so it's very
likely that each pair collides probability
并且如果你知道有b对的话，每一组匹配的碰撞
one over B and if you have B pairs, it's
likely that one of the pairs will collide.
可能性是1/b ,看上去像是配对中的一个会重合。
So hopefully this gives the intuition for
where the square root comes from. Its
这像是给出一个直觉能找到平方根从哪里来的解决方案，
basically from the fact that if you have N
people in the room, there are N squared
它的最基本依据的事实是，你有N个人在房间里，房间里
possible pairs. I should say by the way
that even though the Birthday Paradox is
就有N的平方种可能配对。我必须说虽然生日悖论经常被用来
often applied to birth dates, birth dates
are actually not uniform at all. If you
提供生日日期，但是生日日期并不一定是均匀分布的。
actually look at the birth dates of
people, you see that there is a very clear
如果你真正的调查过人们的生日，你会了解到非常清楚的
bias towards being born in September, and
for me bazaar reason there is also a
生日大多偏向九月，令我惊奇的生日日期偏向周二
biased towards being born on a Tuesday.
And so when we apply the birthday paradox
也偏向周二。所以当我们利用生日悖论去
to birthdays, in fact the actual bound is
going to be smaller than one minus two
预测生日时，在事实上，实际的结合更接近于1减去b的二次方根
square root of B because we said that for
non even form distributions you need even
因为我们说在没有前期分布的情况下，你可能
fewer samples before you get a collision.
So let me show you how to graph the
只需要更少的例子在你得到重合之前。所以让我给你们展示
Birthday Paradox, its quite interesting
how it behaves. So here set B to be a
一下生日悖论的图示，它的走向非常有趣。这里把b以百万
million, in other words we are picking
random uniform samples in the range one to
做单位，换句话说我们是在以百万为单位的样本中
a million. And the X axis here, is the
number of samples that we are picking, and
寻找随机数据。在X轴这里，是我们采摘的例子数目，
the Y axis, is the probability that we get
a collision among those N samples. So we
而Y轴，是我们在N个例子中得到重合的可能性。
see that the probability of one half
happens around 1.2 square root of B.
所以我们可以看出可能性为一半时，大约在1.2倍的B的平方根。
Roughly twelve hundreds, 1.2 square root
of B. And you see that if we look at
大约在1200，也就是1.2倍的b的评分根。你们可以看到
exactly the square root of B, the
probability of a collisions is around .4
如果我们精确的找到b的平方根，重合的可能性大约在
or .41. And you notice that the
probability goes up to one extremely fast.
0.4到0.41之间。你也会注意到可能性增长到一会变得很快。
For example, already at roughly two square
root of B, but the probability of a
举个例子，在大约仅是在两倍的b的平方根处，可可能性
collision is already 90%. Similarly, when
we go bellow square root of B, the
已经是90%、相似的，当我们从那向下走时，
probability of a collision very, very
quickly drops to zero. Okay, so there is
可能性非常快的降到0.好吧，在b的平方根处
kind of a threshold phenomena around
square root of B, where the probability of
存在着临界效应，在此之上，可能性很快
a collision goes to one very quickly,
above square root of B drops to zero very
到1，在此之下，可能性也很快的
quickly below square root of B. So now we
can analyze are attack algorithms, so let
降到0.所以我们现在可以分析这种攻击算法。让我
me remind you, here we chose, two to the
interval two random elements in the
提醒你们这里我们选择两个随机二元空间在
message space, we hashed them. And so we
started off with a random distribution in
信息库中，我们哈希它们。我们从一个在数据库中的随机分布开始
the message base, after we hashed them, we
end up with some distribution, this
在我们分析它之后，我们以一些分布结束，
distribution over tags might note be
uniform, but we don't care, the point is
这些样本的标签可能不是均匀分布的，但是我们不用理会。
that all these tags T1 to T2 to the N over
two, are independent of one another. If we
重要的是这些标签从T1到T2再到二分之N是独立的。
choose. Two to the N over two or 1.2 to
the N over two, tags, the probability that
如果我们选择二到N或者是1.2到二分之N，那么重合的
the collision will exist is roughly one
half. So let me ask you then, in that
可能性将会存在于大约2分之1左右。让我接下来给你看。
case, how many times do we have to iterate
this algorithm before we actually find a
在这种情况下，我们需要按照算法迭代多少次才能找到
collision? Well then since each iteration
is going to find a collision with
重合？每次迭代将会找到一个可能性为二分之一配对
probability one half, we have to iterate
about two times in expectation. And as a
我们在实验中必须迭代两次左右。
result the running time of this algorithm
is basically two to the N over two
该算法的耗费时间是二到二分之n估计的哈希函数的消耗时间。
evaluations of the hash function. Okay so
notice also this algorithm takes a lot of
所以我们也注意到该算法也要占用大量的
space but we're gonna ignore the space
issue and we're just gonna focus on the
空间，我们不去理会空间的因素，我们只把精力放在
running time. Okay so this is kinda cool,
this says that if your hash
消耗时间上。这有点厉害，这就是说如果你的哈希函数
function outputs N-bits outputs
there will always be an attack algorithm
输出N比特的输出，这个攻击算法
that runs in time two to the N over two.
So for example if we output 128 big
将会运行在二到二分之n。举个例子来说就是如果我们输出128比特
outputs Then a collision could be found in
time two to the sixty four, which is not considered
输出，重合就会在二到60小时内被找到。这并没有进行充分的
sufficiently secure. Okay, this is why
collision resistant hash functions,
安全考虑。好吧，这就是为什么哈希函数的反鹏转那个
generally are not going to output 128
bits. So let me show you some examples.
通常不会输出128比特，所以让我给你们看一些例子，
The first three are actually federal
standards, SHA-1, SHA-256, and SHA-512
一分之三通常是联邦标准，而SHA-1,SHA-256,SHA-512和
and the fourth one is an example from
the designers of AES, called Whirlpool,
4是高级加密标准的设计，它们叫做循环环，
and so you can see SHA-1 outputs 160
bits and as a result there is a generic
你也可以看到SHA-1输出160比特并且作为结果，这是一个通用的
attack on it that runs on
time two to the eighty. SHA-256 outputs 256
对它的攻击，在2到80的时间里。SHA-2输出256比特
bits so the generic attack will run
in time two to the 128 and so on and so
所以通用攻击将会在2到128时间内结束并且和4一样。
forth. I also listed the speed of these
algorithms and you notice that the bigger
我也列表了算法的速度，你也会发现最大的块大小
the block size actually the slower the
algorithm is [and?] so there's a
通常也会慢于算法。所以说这样的算法有个
performance penalty but nevertheless
there's quite a bit of benefit in terms of
性能损失但是确实对安全性有益
security. Now you notice the SHA
function is actually greyed out. The
现在你会发现SHA函数确实是灰色输出。
SHA function although nobody has
found collisions for SHA-1 yet
这个SHA函数尽管没有人找到SHA-1的碰撞，但是它还是要求一个新的项目，
It is still recommended that in a new
project, and hopefully programing projects
要求一个新的项目，同时也希望课堂演示
in this class, you don't use SHA-1,
instead you use SHA-256. In particular
不要使用SHA-1，你可以用SHA-256来取代。特殊的，
there is actually a theoretical collision
finder on SHA-1 that works in time two
这里利用SHA-1确实是存在理论上的能找到的碰撞，在消耗
to the 51. So it is probably just a matter
of time until someone finds a collision
时间2到51后。所以说它可能存在时间上的问题直到有人知道
for SHA-1, and just kills altogether,
but the current advice is that SHA-1 is
符合的sha-1的碰撞。但是关于sha-1的正确建议是
still a collision resistant hash function
because nobody has found collisions for
它依然是一个耐碰撞的哈希函数，因为没有人可以找到它的碰撞。
it, but it is probably just a matter of
time, just a few months, or few years,
但是在时间上它可能存在一定的问题可能会花费几个月几年
until a collision is found. It is a result
a new product and new projects SHA-1
直到一个符合的碰撞被找到。这是一个新的创造并且也是新的课题SHA-1
should not be used and only use
SHA-256 or if you wanna be even
不会被应用，只应用SHA-256或者如果你对
more cautious then use SHA-512. So this is the end of this
SHA-512很好奇，你也可以使用它。所以本课将告一段落，
segment, and now we are going to turn
building collision resistant hash
现在我们就可以去建立抗碰撞散列了。